36 Lindsay Road Hooksett, NH 03106

E-mail: spencergsp@aol.com

Lisa L. French, RN, MPH

Phone (603) 623-5823

Summary

Clinician with extensive healthcare experience with a focus on promoting positive change in the areas of business development, product management, disease management, marketing and sales. My areas of expertise include clinical strategy, relationship management, project management and the ability to be flexible in an ever-changing environment. I am creative, intelligent with strong analytical skills, problem solving, communication and interpersonal skills. I am committed to population health management and improving the quality of care.

Professional Experience

4/2010- present OptumInsight (previously Ingenix): Clinical Performance and Compliance

Solution Lead- Care Coordination/Director Prospective Services for Medicare Risk Adjustment

- Responsible for the strategy and program development of our Provider & Member Outreach services. This includes the design, development and launch of existing and new service offerings.
- Provide business development leadership for our member outreach call campaigns, In Home Assessment and Quality programs (Medicare Stars/HEDIS).
- Interact internally and externally with executive management to resolve business problems that affect multiple functions and/or customer accounts.
- Expertise in developing business plans, writing business requirements, leading cross-functional teams and overseeing the development of a solution.
- Manage Home Based Office

3/2008- 4/2010 Comprehensive Health Solutions/ WellPoint

Manchester, NH

Sr. Product Manager:

ConditionCare Disease Management Programs

- Subject Matter Expert for WellPoint's the disease management programs which covers 34 million members and the project manager of our cross functional CORE team. Care management programs include the following conditions; Diabetes, CAD, HF, COPD, Asthma, Hypertension, Hyperlipidemia, Metabolic Syndrome, Low Back Pain, Musculoskeletal and several oncology conditions.
- Responsible for the design and development of products in both new and existing markets.
- Coordinates the presentation, communication and implementation of all phases of product development from operations, marketing, sales, analytics, IT, quality and health coaching. Ensures products are compliant with regulatory directives and state/federal laws and policies.
- Project managed multiple project plans for new vendor solutions from concept through to successful implementation. Delivered an integrated and customized solution for our clients for the following enhancements to our programs; the use of interactive voice response technology (Eliza and Televox), social media tool (Social Kinetics) and health education materials (Healthwise).
- Participated in the clinical workflow design and development of our member centric clinical decision support Assessment Tool for the new integrated health management solutions (go-live 4/2010).
- Participated in the overhaul of the programs clinical outcome metrics (HEDIS), alignment of our programs clinical goals and developed customized member educational materials for all of our conditions.

Director of Client Solutions

- Member of the clinical consultant team for a web-based, data-mining and health care intelligence Software Company.
- Clinical SME for product development of our disease management and/or case management software tools.
- Performed advanced medical analytics using cost and quality metrics, with reporting and ongoing evaluations to determine the effectiveness of our client's disease management and/or case management programs.
- Member of the clinical team that was responsible for the development and implementation of evidenced based clinical rules within the software.
- Project lead for NCQA certification and alignment of clinical rules to HEDIS performance metrics.
- Performed strategic consultation and presentations to our clinical customers which included; product WebEx demo's, staff training, workflow analysis, and support of clinical and operational initiatives through product enhancements.
- Provided support to the sales, account management, and marketing teams (including RFP's).
- Our clients include health plans, TPA's, disease management companies as well as medical device and pharmaceutical companies.

8/2003-7/2007 Healthway's, Inc. / BCBSMA Account

Boston, MA

Provider Services Manager

- Responsible for business planning and the strategic marketing of our disease management programs (CAD, Diabetes, CKD, HF) with the goal of improving the clinical performance measures of our customer.
- Project Manager for Quality Assessment Performance Improvement (QAPI) Heart Failure study for 3
 years within provider offices. Coordinated the data collection of more than 800 medical records.
- Performed medical analytics of performance metrics with the study.
- Developed and maintained relationships with our Physician Advisory Committee that was responsible for ongoing evaluation of our programs.
- Utilized tools in the form of best practice guidelines, outcome reports, and practice workflow assessments resulting in action plans that optimize patient health outcomes.
- Conducted clinical consultative calls and responsible for the management of the Northern Region of Massachusetts providers, >600 physicians with various EMR systems.
- Managed field based position from home office.

8/2002- 5/2003 Medtronic, Inc.

ME, NH, VT

Clinical Specialist-Nurse Educator - Neurology

- Primary clinical support and sales resource for our Activa and ITB therapies.
- Increased sales of ITB SynchroMed pumps from 75% to 123% of quota. Conducted sales calls on targeted market of long-term care facilities, home health agencies, physicians and OR staff.
- Managed OR case coverage, education and referral development.
- Provided in-services and other teaching/training opportunities as needed. Applied clinical knowledge to trouble-shoot and solve problems.
- Supported patients with Essential Tremor, Parkinson's, MS, Brain Injury, CP, Stroke and Spinal Cord Injury to provide additional education.
- Managed field based position from home office.

Clinical Quality Improvement Specialist

- Served as the primary clinical liaison for Centers for Medicare & Medicaid Services (CMS) National Heart Failure Practice Improvement Study. Accountable for managing multiple phases of the project, which included working with 20 Primary Care and Cardiology Physicians' offices in Maine, New Hampshire and Vermont.
- Achieved a participation rate of 90% for the practices in the project and reviewed the 422 medical records that met the definition for heart failure.
- Developed and conducted individualized in-service sessions and provided performance metric reporting and evaluations to each of the 20 sites to senior level physicians. These presentations also include clinical training of the entire staff, which often included physicians, nurses, medical assistants and support personnel. Worked with the practices on workflow and system improvement solutions.
- Collaborated both internally with our Physicians, Data Analysts, Epidemiologists, Outreach Coordinators and Information Systems Personal and externally with Medical Directors, Quality Improvement Directors, Office Managers and Physicians.
- Supported the Diabetes project by performing data collection and attended the intervention sessions.

7/1999- 3/2000 Merck & Co., Inc.

Territory, NH

Cardiovascular Specialty Sales Representative

- Completed the 10-week cardiovascular specialty-training course. Ranked highest in class.
- As primary contact, responsible for the overall management of business relationships with targeted therapeutic specialists, focusing primarily on the sales of Merck products and services. Increased the specification of Merck products in appropriate patients by effectively communicating with medical, paramedical and administrative persons who influence the use of Merck products.
- Maximized development and productivity of local advocates and improved the adoption of Merck products in specialist audiences through patient and practice management.
- Maintained expertise regarding customer issues, diseases, market and product information. Developed territory business plan to prioritize opportunities and maximize effectiveness.
- Managed field based position from home office.

3/1998-8/1999

Manchester, NH

Health Risk Management Program Manager- Cardiovascular Disease Management

Blue Cross and Blue Shield of New Hampshire

- Primary function was the development, implementation and management of SmartCare for CHF, a disease
 management program for BCBS members diagnosed with Congestive Heart Failure. This program received
 a National award from Healthcare Innovations in Technology Systems (HITS) "Partnerships in Technology"
 for 2000. The HITS award was created in 1992 by the Henry Ford Health System to honor collaborative
 efforts of healthcare organizations and technology vendors for creative use of new or emerging technology to
 improve the quality of patient care
- Member of the implementation team for Confer web-enabled disease management software. Produced and developed the algorithm design of the congestive heart failure workflow, clinical outcomes, interventions and reporting.
- Traveled to Redwood City, San Francisco with the technical support personnel, to provide critical feedback prior to installation. Worked with the software developers and the project manager regarding the custom designed CHF disease management software.
- Liaison to Confers clinical specialist and project manager to ensure proper design and application of the

1/93-2/98 BCBS of Maine

South Portland, ME

On-site Utilization Review Case Manager/ Cardiac Disease Management Case Manager

- On-site case manager: reviewed charts of patients with cardiovascular disease, oncology, neurology, special
 care units, coronary care units and pediatrics to ensure appropriate treatment plan and length of stay.
- Experience using MEDecision collaborative care management software
- Consulted with external cardiovascular and oncology physicians to reduce inpatient utilization and address appropriate medical treatment options.
- 12/96-Promoted to Cardiovascular Case Manager- Responsible for the telephonic management of members with cardiovascular disease, such as post-myocardial infarction, angina, angioplasty and bypass surgery.
- Worked collaboratively in the product development of cardiovascular, diabetes, and asthma disease management programs; including member questionnaires, policies and procedures and case management interventions.

5/85-1/93 Clinical Positions Include:

The Elms Residence: Long Term Care Facility

(1992) Director of Infection Control, Quality Assurance, and Staff Education.

South Portland VNA:

(1991) Home Health Nurse. Care of patients in their homes, blood draws and teaching.

Brighton Medical Center:

(1988-1989) Coronary Intensive Care Unit (ICU). Care of patients post myocardial infarction, chest pain, pulmonary edema and respiratory failure.

Mercy Hospital:

(1987-1988, 1990) Orthopedics Unit. Care of patient's post-spinal surgery, hip fractures and Knee repairs.

Maine Medical Center:

(1989-1990) Special Care Unit (ICU). Care of trauma patients, post coronary artery bypass surgery and respiratory failure.

(1985-1987) Neurology (ICU) /Urology Unit. Care of patients post urology surgery, spinal surgery and trauma.

Education

9/2003- 12/07 University of New Hampshire

Manchester, NH

Masters in Public Health in Nursing

5/1993 University of Southern Maine

Portland, ME

Bachelors Degree in Nursing : Graduated Summa Cum Laude